MetaMetrics®’ Global Privacy Policy

Updated June 2023

Introduction and Key Definitions

This is the Global Privacy Policy (this “Privacy Policy”) of MetaMetrics, Inc., (“MetaMetrics”,

“we,” “our” or “us”). We want our visitors to learn about our services, and we help educators,

researchers, parents, students, and other authorized users to easily put the Lexile Framework®

for Reading, Lexile Framework® for Oral Reading and the Quantile Framework® for

Mathematics to work. In this Privacy Policy we describe the information we may collect about

you through our Sites (as defined in our Terms of Use), how we use that information,

circumstances in which we share it, how we protect it, and the rights and choices you may have

with regard to your information. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully before accessing or

using our Sites. By accessing or using any of our Sites, you accept and agree to be bound by

this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, do not access or use our Sites.

This Privacy Policy is incorporated into our Terms of Use. Any capitalized terms not defined in

this Privacy Policy have the definitions set forth in the Terms of Use.

In the event we add future Sites or services that affect the terms of this Privacy Policy, we will

revise accordingly. References to “you” or “your” pertain to all our site visitors, registered users,

or Hub members throughout this Privacy Policy.

What is our general approach to your PersonalInformation?

We do not sell Personal Information as that term is commonly defined in applicable privacy

laws. We use reasonable efforts to protect information that identifies, relates to, describes, is

capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked with you or your household

(your “Personal Information”).

We know that when users provide Personal Information to an organization it is an act of trust.

That trust is something we take seriously. MetaMetrics works to ensure that the Sites observe

compliance standards for online privacy, security, business practices, honest transactions, and

availability. This Privacy Policy explains the steps we take to protect Personal Information

shared with us through the Sites or when you otherwise interact with us, including how we

collect it, who has access to it and what is done with it.

NOTICE AT COLLECTION

What categories of Personal Information do we collect?

The categories of Personal Information we collect and use include the following (these are

examples and may be subject to change):

1

Identity Data Information such as your name; address; email address; telephone

number; age and/or age range; or other account-related information;

and information you provide in connection with your application to be

an employee or to otherwise collaborate with us.

Contact Data Identity Data that relates to information about how we can

communicate with you, such as email, phone numbers, physical

addresses, and information you provide to us when you contact us by

email or otherwise communicate with us.

General Location

Data Non-precise information about your location as determined based on

your IP address.

Device/Network Data Browsing history, search history, and information regarding your

interaction with our Sites (e.g. IP Address, MAC Address, SSIDs or

other device identifiers or persistent identifiers), online user ID, device

characteristics (such as browser/OS version), web server logs,

application logs, browsing data, first party cookies, third party cookies,

web beacons, clear gifs and pixel tags.

Commercial Data Information about the services for which you have registered and

transactions you enter into with us, and similar information.

Inference Data Personal Information used to create a profile about you, which may

include your preferences, reading or writing levels, abilities, aptitudes,

and other data or analytics provided about you or your account by our

third party partners or data aggregators.

Audio/Visual Data Data collected if you submit audio or video recordings to our Sites or

services, as well as any other audio or video files you may submit to

us, in addition to voice mails, call recordings, and the like.

User Content Unstructured/free-form data that may include any category of

Personal Information, e.g. data that you give us in free text fields such

as comment boxes, answers you provide when you participate in

sweepstakes, contests, votes and surveys, including any other

Personal Information which you may provide through or in connection

with our Services.

Sensitive Personal

Information

Personal Information deemed “sensitive” under California or other

laws, such as social security, driver’s license, state identification card,

or passport number; account log-in and password, financial account,

debit card, or credit card number; precise location data; racial or

ethnic origin, religious or philosophical beliefs, etc. We collect the

following categories of Sensitive Personal Information:● “Account Log-In Data” Information you need to log-in to your

account on our services, including your user name and password.● “Financial Data” Information such as bank account details,

payment card information, including similar data defined in Cal Civ

Code § 1798.80(e), which is collected only to the extent you have

subscribed to one of our paid services.

2

What are the purposes for which we collect and usePersonal Information?

Information we collect automatically

Some information, typically including Device/Network Data, is collected automatically when you

visit the Sites. This information may not on its own reveal your name or contact information, but

it may include device and usage information, such as your IP address, browser, device

characteristics, operating system, language preferences, referring URLs, device name, country,

location, information about how and when you use the Sites and other technical information.

How we use this information: This information is primarily needed to maintain the security

and operation of the Sites, and for our internal analytics and reporting purposes, however we

also use this information to improve our Sites and services, to determine which features of our

Sites are most popular with our users, and to otherwise better understand our users’

preferences.

The technologies we use for this automatic data collection may include:

● Cookies (or browser cookies). “Cookies” are small text files that are placed on

your device by a Web server when you access The Sites. We may use both

session Cookies and persistent Cookies to tell us how and when you interact with

the Sites, as well as to keep you logged-in to our Sites, and to otherwise improve

your experience on our Sites. We may also use Cookies to monitor aggregate

usage, remember your preferences, and to customize and improve the Sites.

Unlike persistent Cookies, session Cookies are deleted when you navigate away

from the Sites and close your browser. Although most browsers automatically

accept Cookies, you can change your browser options to stop automatically

accepting Cookies or to prompt you before accepting Cookies. Please note,

however, that if you don’t accept Cookies, you may not be able to access all

portions or features of the Sites. Some “essential” Cookies are required for our

Sites to function properly, and other “non-essential” Cookies are helpful to enable

certain features, but you are still able to use our Site without them (although

certain features or functionality may be disabled). You may modify your

preferences with regard to our use of non-essential Cookies by reviewing our

Cookie Policy and selecting your preferences with regard to non-essential

Cookies. Please note that some Service Providers that we engage may also

place their own Cookies on your device. Note that this Privacy Policy covers only

our use of Cookies and does not include use of Cookies by any Third Party or

Service Provider you visit directly. Both should have their own privacy policies.

● Web Beacons. Pages of the Sites and our e-mails may contain small electronic

files known as web beacons (also referred to as clear gifs, pixel tags, and

single-pixel gifs) that permit us, for example, to count users who have visited

those pages or opened an email and for other related website statistics (for

example, recording the popularity of certain website content and verifying system

and server integrity).

3

Information you voluntarily provide

We collect Personal Information from and about you when you voluntarily provide it to us, in

addition to Personal Information and other data we collect automatically when you visit the

Sites. Depending on the Site you have accessed, or the other ways in which you interact with

us, we may collect different types of information as outlined below.

Website/Services Users

Generally: We process Device/Network Data, Contact Data, Identity Data, General LocationData, and Inference Data when you visit our Sites. You may also be able to create an account,enroll in marketing communications, or use various services through our Sites, which are furtherdescribed below. We use this Personal Information as necessary to operate our Sites, such askeeping you logged in, delivering pages, etc., for our Business Purposes described below, andour other legitimate interests, such as:● ensuring the security of our websites, mobile applications and other technology

systems; and● analyzing the use of our Sites, including navigation patterns, clicks, etc. to help

understand and make improvements to the Sites.

Account Creation: Some of our Sites enable you to register to create an account. If you do this,

we will collect Account Log-In Data, Identity Data and Contact Data, including the username,

email address, and password you provide. We may also collect General Location Data based

on your IP Address, and Device/Network Data when you access our Sites. On some Sites we

may also request additional Personal Information associated with your account (such as your

age, company name, school, or other data indicated in the form when you create your account).

We use Account Log-In Data, Identity Data and Contact Data in connection with logging you in

to our Sites, managing your account and your use of our Sites and services.

Subscriptions: If you purchase a subscription to one of our Sites, we will collect Account Log-In

Data, Identity Data, Contact Data, Financial Data and Commercial Data,. Some Sites may

additionally require role (educator, parent, researcher), General Location Data such as country

or US state, and company. We process this Personal Information as necessary to perform or

initiate a subscription with you, process your order, payment, or refund, carry out fulfillment and

delivery, document transactions, and for our Business Purposes.

● For certain subscriptions, we may also require that you provide Financial Data,

Identity Data and Contact Data, including billing information, to our payment

processor Service Provider, Stripe Elements. Note that qualifying educators in

Lexile and Quantile partner states can subscribe to some of our Sites for free and

thus without the need to provide billing information. All registered users may

voluntarily submit additional Personal Information, like their first and last name,

into their Profile information and select mailing lists to which they wish to

subscribe.

● Payment card data is subject to the Payment Card Industry Data Security

Standard (PCI DSS), which is a set of security standards designed to ensure that

all companies that accept, process, store or transmit credit card information

maintain a secure environment. If you submit a payment to us via credit or debit

card, you will be transferred to the site of our third party payment processor,

Stripe Elements, a pre-built user interface (UI) component created by Stripe, Inc.

4

When you enter into a paid subscription for one of our Sites, sensitive credit card

data is exchanged using direct communication between the Stripe UI component

in your browser and the Stripe service. MetaMetrics has no access to this data.

We do not collect, control, see or store any of the card data entered into Stripe

Elements. The Stripe service creates a token and returns it to our web service

as a record of successful payment. This token is a virtual object that represents

the actual, sensitive data, which is designed to better protect your data.

● See Stripe’s Privacy Policy for more details available at www.stripe.com/privacy.

Special Offers and Demonstration Versions: We may offer limited time, seasonal, early or

limited access, special purpose or demonstration versions of our Sites or tools. In such cases

we may collect additional Personal Information, which may include Identity Data, Contact Data,

General Location Data, and Commercial Data, tied to the registrant’s email, role, country, and

state, and potentially also including grade level, math or reading level, school district, and

quantile measure, depending on the offering. Where applicable, we may permit users to provide

student data in order to customize the registered user’s use of the offered service.

Inquiries and Support

Certain pages on some of our Sites enable you to submit inquiries or requests to us, in which

case we may collect Identity Data, Contact Data, User Content, Account Log-In Data,

Commercial Data, and potentially Device/Network Data. These Sites collect this Personal

Information when users complete an inquiry or request for more information using our online

form. These forms typically collect the following information: first and last name, phone

number, email address, organization name, organization type, areas of interest. We may share

this information with our third party service providers, including storing the information in

cloud-based contact management systems, and providing the information to third parties who

assist us with our email marketing and other communications.

Any user of our Sites wishing to obtain support must provide an email address. Without this

information we cannot answer your questions. When submitting a support question to us

through Hub Support Contact Us you must not only provide a valid email address, but also first

and last name, US state if applicable, country, role, and your specified request. Some of our

Sites offer multiple levels of access, some of which may require users to register or purchase a

subscription, in which case we would collect Financial Data, and others which are available

without registration or subscription. Differences between levels of access may require

corresponding differences in data collection practices.

We may also collect Identity Data, contact Data, Account Log-In Data, Commercial Data, or

Audio/Visual Data if you contact us for support via phone or video conference.

Oral Reading Performance Measurement

You may be able to submit oral reading samples to some of our Sites, in which case we may

collect Identity Data, Contact Data, Account Log-In Data, User Content, Audio/Visual Data, and

potentially Device/Network Data. These Sites may enable users to record themselves reading a

presented passage or to upload an audio file of themselves or others reading. When we collect

oral reading samples, data collected may include the reader’s grade (if a student), session ID,

date and time of the recording, and prior ability information used to calculate current oral

reading ability. Information we send back as a result of the analysis may also be linked to data

5

or files retained in our system. We may use a Third Party provider for automated speech

recognition (ASR). Once processed, an informational Lexile oral reading ability measure is

displayed. This measure is not to be used for educational placement of a child or for

identification of speech disorders or other diagnosis of an adult.

Listening Content Measurement

You may be able to submit audio books and audio passages to some of our Sites, which may

involve collection of Identity Data, Contact Data, Account Log-In Data, User Content,

Audio/Visual Data, and potentially Device/Network Data. We may process Inference Data as

part of our analysis These Sites may enable users to upload one or more audio files as an audio

complexity measurement job. When we collect Listening Content, data collected may include

the user’s name, user ID, company name, company ID, session ID, date and time of the upload,

audio title, publisher name, ISBN, job name and job number, and other bibliographic data as

may be relevant. Information we send back as a result of the analysis may also be linked to

data or files retained in our system. Once processed, a Lexile listening complexity measure is

displayed or sent.

Note, however, that when you submit a voice recording through one of our Sites, it may be

processed by a Third Party ASR provider. Data sent by MetaMetrics to a Third Party is

anonymized and is encrypted while in transit, protecting all Personal Information connected with

the reader. To the extent that the reader is a child, we encourage you to review and approve the

third party’s Privacy Policy prior to submitting your child’s voice recording to them. We may use

one or more third parties and do not control or direct their processing of your Personal

Information, and as such we are not responsible for their management of your data.

Marketing Communications

We may use Account Log-In Data, Identity Data, Contact Data, Inference Data, and

Device/Network Data for marketing communications, including to send you emails regarding

other MetaMetrics products and services we believe would be of interest to you, and when you

open or interact with those emails. You may receive marketing communications if you consent

and, in some jurisdictions, as a result of account registration or a purchase. See your rights and

choices below to opt out of marketing communications.

Information collected from other sources

We may collect limited data from schools with which we have a relationship, public databases,

marketing partners, and other outside sources. This may include Identity Data, Contact Data,

General Location Data, Device/Network Data, and Inference Data. All Personal Information that

you provide on or to a Third Party or that is collected by a Third Party is provided directly to the

controller, owner or operator of the Third Party and is subject to the owner’s or operator’s

privacy policy. We do not monitor or control any data you provide to Third Parties. Thus, we

are not responsible for the content, privacy or security practices of a Third Party. To assure the

protection of your Personal Information, we recommend that you carefully review the privacy

policies of any Third Party you access. You assume the risk of providing any information you

provide to a Third Party.

6

Business Purposes of Processing

We and our Service Providers process Personal Information for several common business

purposes, depending on the context of collection, your rights and choices, and our legitimate

interests. We generally process Personal Information for the following “Business Purposes,”

however, further details on how we use specific categories of Personal Information in various

aspects of our business is provided above.

Providing our Sites and Services

We process any Personal Information as is necessary to provide the Sites, and as otherwise

necessary to fulfil our obligations to you, e.g. to provide you with the information and Sites you

request, to manage our organization, to collect amounts owing to us, to maintain business

records for reasonable periods and to satisfy regulatory requirements.

Internal Processes and Service Improvement

We may use any Personal Information we process through our Sites as necessary in connection

with our improvement of the design of our Sites, understanding how our Sites are used or

function, for customer service purposes, in connection with the creation and analysis of logs and

metadata relating to service use, and for ensuring the security and stability of the Sites.

Additionally, we may use Personal Information to understand what parts of our Sites are most

relevant to our users, how users interact with various aspects of our Sites, how our Sites

perform, etc., or we may analyze use of the Sites to determine if there are specific activities that

might indicate an information security risk to the Sites or our users. This processing is subject to

certain user rights and choices as described further below.

Compliance, Safety \& Public Interest

Note that we may, without your consent or further notice to you, and to the extent required or

permitted by law, process any Personal Information subject to this Policy for purposes

determined to be in the public interest or otherwise required by law. For example, we may

process information as necessary to fulfil our legal obligations, to protect the vital interests of

any individuals, or otherwise in the public interest or as required by a public authority. Please

see the data sharing section for more information about how we disclose Personal Information

in extraordinary circumstances.

Aggregate Analytics

When an individual visits our Sites, our organization processes Personal Information as

necessary in our creation of aggregate analytics to better understand how our Sites are used, to

make sure our content and services are served correctly, and to improve the performance of our

Sites. The resulting aggregate data will not contain information from which an individual may be

readily identified.

Personalization

7

We process certain Personal Information in connection with our legitimate business interest in

personalizing our Sites. For example, aspects of the Sites may be customized to you based on

your interactions with our Sites and other content. This processing may involve the creation and

use of Inference Data relating to your preferences.

How long do we keep Personal Information?

In general, we keep Personal Information as long as it is reasonably necessary in connection

with the purpose for which it was provided, or for so long as is required by law. What is

necessary may vary depending on the context and purpose of processing. For data collected

from registered Members, we will keep Personal Information for as long as a Member maintains

registration and or subscription in good standing. Once those registrations or subscriptions

lapse or terminate, unless a written agreement between us and a Member provides otherwise,

we may keep Personal Information for as long as needed only to meet regulatory requirements

or business requirements. Any kept Personal Information will remain subject to the restrictions

on sharing and use outlined in this Policy for as long as it resides with us.

We generally consider the following factors when we determine how long to retain data (without

limitation):● Retention periods established under applicable law;● Industry best practices;● Whether the purpose of processing is reasonably likely to justify further processing;● Risks to individual privacy in continued processing;● Applicable data protection impact assessments;● IT systems design considerations/limitations; and● The costs associated continued processing, retention, and deletion.

We will review retention periods periodically and may pseudonymize or anonymize data held for

longer periods.

Do we sell your Personal Information or “share” it for

behavioral advertising purposes?

We do not “sell” or “share” (for behavioral advertising purposes) your Personal Information (as

that term is defined under applicable privacy laws), and as such you do not have to Opt-in or

Opt-out of any sale or sharing of Personal Information.

DISCLOSURES OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

What and how do we disclose to Service Providers?

In order to operate our business it may sometimes be necessary to disclose Personal

Information with contractors and other service providers. Personal Information disclosed to

8

Service Providers may include Contact Data, Identity Data, Commercial Data, Device/Network

Data, General Location Data, Audio/Visual Data, Inference Data, and User Content. In limited

situations, depending on the services provided by the Service Provider, we may provide them

Financial Data. For example, we may share Personal Information with the companies that host

our Sites, provide analytics and other functionality on our Sites, host or provide our database of

current and potential customers, help us send emails and other communications, or provide

other services to us. In addition, we may share Personal Information with individual contractor

scientists and software developers as may be required.

As noted above, we use third-party service providers to analyze audio recordings. When the

recording is submitted to the third party for processing, we share only Audio/Video Recording

Data, and no other personal identifiers are shared. Results from the third party are combined

with our own processes to calculate the reader’s proficiency results. In doing so, we connect

the proficiency results with the Personal Information you provided.

All Service Providers are bound by a legal contract to keep Personal Information confidential.

They can use Personal Information only for the purposes for which we disclose it.

● Google Analytics-- We use Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google

Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics is a web analysis tool we use to help us

analyze the interaction of visitors with our Sites. Thus, we can improve your

experience on our Sites. Google Analytics uses Cookies. The information

generated by the Cookie regarding your use of the Sites are usually transferred

to a server belonging to Google. The information saved by the Cookies includes,

for instance, the time of your visit on the Sites, the frequency with which the

visitor has called up the Sites, and from where the visitor has accessed the Sites.

To determine the latter value, Google initially records the IP address of the user.

However, we have activated the IP anonymization on the Sites. On behalf of the

Sites, Google will use the aforementioned information to analyze your usage of

the Sites, to compile reports on the Sites’ activities and to provide further

services associated with the usage of the Sites and the Internet. You can

prevent Google Analytics from saving the Cookies by a corresponding setting in

your browser software. However, by doing so you may disable some functions of

the Sites. In addition, you can prevent the recording of the data generated by the

Cookie and relating to your usage of the Sites (including your IP address) to

Google and the processing of these data by Google, by downloading and

installing the browser plug-in available under the following link:

http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl Further information on data protection

with regard to Google Analytics can be found at said link.

Further information about handling user data can be found

at https://developers.google.com/fonts/faq and in Google’s privacy policy at

https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/.

Please check this Privacy Policy regularly for updates on other Service Providers that may be

used in connection with the Sites or contact us at Hub Support Contact Us for the most recent

list of our Service Providers with whom we share your information.

9

What and how do we disclose to other third parties?

Fulfilling your requests. Some of our Sites include the ability for you to share content or

information with third parties you designate. If you give us an email address to use the “share”

feature within a tool, we will transmit the contents of that email and your email address to the

recipients.

Affiliated entities and corporate transactions. We may share Personal Information with our

current or future subsidiaries and affiliates in order to streamline provision of services or for

other business purposes. In addition, if we contemplate a merger, divestiture, restructuring,

reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some or all of our assets, it is possible

that we would need to share Personal Information with another organization during the

due-diligence process, following the transaction, or otherwise in connection with a corporate

event.

Partners. We may disclose your Personal Information to partners, such as schools or schoolboards, in order to provide our Sites.

Legal disclosures. We may also share Personal Information to comply with a court order, law

or legal process. This includes a government or regulatory request. Before we do that, we

would provide the user with notice of the requirement. If the user so chooses, a protective order

or another remedy could be sought. If after providing that notice we still must share the

demanded Personal Information, we will share no more than that portion of Personal

Information which, on the advice of our legal counsel, the order, law or process specifically

requires us to share. Note, some of these disclosures may be made to governments that do not

ensure the same degree of protection of your Personal Information as your home jurisdiction.

We may, in our sole discretion (but without any obligation) object to the disclosure of your

Personal Information to such parties.

Other parties. We may share Personal Information with third parties as we deem appropriate

in order to enforce or apply our Terms of Use, Additional Terms, or other agreements, including

for billing and collection purposes, to prevent fraud, and to obtain advice about legal and

financial matters.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Children’s Information

We do not directly collect personal information from children through our Sites. We may receive

data provided by a parent regarding their child (which may include the child’s Identity

Information, Audio/Visual Data, or Sensitive Personal Information), or by a state, school district

or teacher containing information regarding a child or groups of children, however, any group

information is aggregated and anonymized such that it no longer is considered Personal

Information under applicable laws. If you believe that we have collected Personal Information

directly from a child under the age of 13 (in the U.S.) or 16 (typically the applicable age in

European countries) without following the proper procedures, please notify us via email to

support@lexile.com.

10

What data security measures do we take?

MetaMetrics has reasonable safeguards to help prevent unauthorized access to, disclosure of,

or misuse of your Personal Information. However, we cannot guarantee that your Personal

Information will never be shared or otherwise processed in a manner inconsistent with this

Privacy Policy (for example, as a result of unauthorized acts by third parties that violate

applicable law or our Terms of Use).

If you register for a membership with the Hub or similar Sites we offer, you will be asked to

select a password to help protect your Personal Information. These passwords help us verify

your identity before granting access or making corrections to any of your Personal Information.

You should never share your password with anyone. MetaMetrics will never ask you for your

password in a phone call or email. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your

passwords and any account information.

When subscribing for Premium membership through the Hub you also provide your credit card

information. It is transmitted using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to help prevent

unauthorized access or misuse of that information. (PCI-compliance requires following the

Transport Layer Security 1.2 rules.) SSL is the standard security technology for establishing an

encrypted link between a web server and a browser. Make sure you see a full “lock” symbol

and https in the status bar of your browser. Browsers like Firefox 63 and above, Google

Chrome 70 and above, Safari 6.2 and above employ some version of the lock symbol to indicate

security. If the lock symbol is not visible, do not enter any information. Direct any issues or

concerns to our support community for further guidance at Hub Support Contact Us.

Finally, the computers/servers in which MetaMetrics stores Personal Information are kept in a

secure environment.

Please note that to the extent your Personal Information is shared with a service provider or

other third party, we cannot guarantee, nor will we be responsible for, the security measures of

those third parties.

INTERNATIONAL DATA

Legal Basis for Processing

We process your Personal Information in accordance with applicable data protection laws. If

you are subject to the GDPR, we process Personal Information in accordance with one of the

required legal bases. For example, when you voluntarily provide Personal Information to us, we

primarily process it with your consent, or in order to fulfill a contract with you. Information we

collect automatically is typically processed in accordance with our legitimate business interests,

such as to improve our Sites and services. We may also process certain Personal Information

to the extent required by applicable legal requirements.

International Data Transfers

MetaMetrics is a U.S. company. If you are located outside the United States and choose to

provide information to us, we transfer at least some Personal Information to the United States

for processing, and our service providers may process Personal Information in the United States

11

and elsewhere. These countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country in

which you initially provided the information. When we transfer your information to the United

States, we will protect it as described in this Notice. Data we collect may be transferred to,

stored, and processed in any country or territory where one or more of our affiliates or service

providers are based or have facilities. While other countries or territories may not have the

same standards of data protection as those in your home country, we will continue to protect

Personal Information that we transfer in line with this Privacy Policy.

If you are located in the European Economic Area (“EEA”), please note that some countries

outside the EEA do not have laws that protect your privacy rights as extensively as those in the

EEA. However, if we do transfer your Personal Information to other territories, we will put in

place appropriate safeguards designed to ensure that your Personal Information will be

protected and processed in accordance with this Privacy Policy and the requirements of

applicable data protection laws, including, when applicable, the General Data Protection

Regulation (“GDPR”) or the UK GDPR (as defined in UK Data Protection Act 2018). We may

transfer Personal Information from the EEA to the US using the EU or UK (as applicable)

standard contractual clauses or other lawful mechanisms.

PERSONAL INFORMATION RIGHTS ANDCHOICES

How can you exercise rights in your PersonalInformation?

At any time, Members of the Hub or our other Sites offering subscription options can change

their Personal Information stored in The Profile page. Members can also choose to opt-out of

MetaMetrics’ mailing lists with immediate impact. Members can also close their Hub

memberships by following the directions listed in the Hub for immediate closure of the

membership. Closing a membership will not trigger the deletion of Personal Information.

Regardless of whether you are a Member, depending on where you live, and subject to our

obligations under applicable laws, you may have certain rights and choices regarding your

Personal Information. Please note, these rights may vary based on the country or state where

you reside, and our obligations under applicable law.

Verification of Rights Requests

If you submit a request, we typically must verify your identity to ensure that you have the right to

make that request, reduce fraud, and to ensure the security of Personal Information. If an agent

is submitting the request on your behalf, we reserve the right to validate the agent’s authority to

act on your behalf.

We may require that you match Personal Information we have on file in order to adequately

verify your identity. If you have an account, we may require that you log into the account to

submit the request as part of the verification process. We may not grant access to certain

Personal Information to you if prohibited by law.

12

Regional Rights

● Access Rights: You may have the right to receive certain information, such as

the following (these rights, and the applicable types of data and time periods, will

vary depending on the laws applicable to the state or country in which you

reside):

● Access to and/or a copy of certain Personal Information we hold about

you.● You may have the right to obtain certain Personal Information in a

portable format.● California residents also have the right to obtain information about: 1) the

categories of Personal Information we have collected or disclosed about

you; (2) the categories of sources of such information; (3) the business or

commercial purpose for collecting or selling your Personal Information; (4)

the categories of third parties to whom we disclosed Personal Information;

and (5) the right to confirm whether we are processing your Personal

Information.

● Erasure: You may have the right to request that we delete certain Personal

Information we have about you. We may either decide to delete your Personal

Information entirely, or we may anonymize or aggregate your Personal

Information such that it no longer reasonably identifies you. Certain Personal

Information may be exempt from such requests under applicable law. For

example, we need certain types of information so that we can provide our

services to you, we may be required to retain certain information for legal

purposes, and there may be other reasons we may need to keep certain

Personal Information under various applicable laws. In addition, if you ask us to

delete your Personal Information, you may no longer be able to access or use

some of our tools or services.

● Correction: You may have the right to request that we correct certain Personal

Information we hold about you.

● Limitation of Processing: Certain laws may allow you to object to or limit the

manner in which we process some of your Personal Information, including the

ways in which we use or share it. For example, you may have these rights if the

processing was undertaken without your consent in connection with our

legitimate business interests (although we may not be required to cease or limit

processing in cases where our interests are balanced against your privacy

interests).

● Regulator Contact: You may have the right to contact or file a complaint with

regulators or supervisory authorities about our processing of Personal

Information. To do so, please contact your local data protection or consumer

protection authority.

● Postings by Minors: Users of our Sites under the age of 18 in certain

jurisdictions have the right to require that we delete any content they have posted

on one of our Sites.

● Non-Discrimination: California residents have the right to not to receive

discriminatory treatment as a result of your exercise of rights conferred by the

CCPA.

13

● Other: You may have the right to receive information about the financial

incentives that we offer to you, if any. You may also have the right to not be

discriminated against (as provided for in applicable law) for exercising certain of

your rights.

If you believe that you have specific rights under your jurisdiction and you would like to exercise

any of these rights, please submit a support request through Hub Support Contact Us or email

us at support@lexile.com. Other than marketing opt-out and do-not-sell requests, you will be

required to verify your identity before we fulfill your request. In certain jurisdictions, you may be

able to designate an authorized agent to make a request on your behalf, subject to certain

requirements of your applicable law. We may require that you provide the email address we

have on file for you (and verify that you can access that email account) as well as an address,

phone number, or other data we have on file, in order to verify your identity. If an agent is

submitting the request on your behalf, we reserve the right to validate the agent’s authority to

act on your behalf, and we may be required to take additional verification measures under

applicable law.

Opt-Out of Sale and “Sharing” for Behavioral Advertising

MetaMetrics does not currently “sell” or “share” for behavioral advertising (as defined by the

California Consumer Privacy Act and other U.S. state laws) any Personal Information subject to

this Privacy Policy, and we do not exchange Personal Information for any type of financial

incentive. However, if you wish to be placed on our “do not sell or share” list in the event that

we begin selling Personal Information or sharing it for behavioral advertising purposes in the

future, please submit a request through Hub Support Contact Us or send an email to

support@lexile.com and request to be added to this list.

Categories of Sensitive Personal Data Used or Disclosed

For purposes of CCPA, we may use or disclose the following categories of Sensitive Personal

Information: Account Log-In Data and Financial Data. However, we only process Sensitive

Personal Information for certain limited purposes as permitted under the CCPA, such as

performing Services as reasonably expected, to prevent, detect, and investigate security

incidents, to resist malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal actions, to ensure the physical

safety of natural persons, for short-term transient use, to verify or maintain the quality or safety

of a product, service, or device, or for purposes that do not infer characteristics about

individuals.

Cookies, Similar Technologies, and Targeted Advertising

Opt-Out: If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, you can

manage/deny cookies (and certain technologies) using your browser’s settings menu or our

Manage Cookies page located at https://policies.metametricsinc.com/Manage_Cookies.pdf. You

may need to opt out of cookies and similar technologies on third-party sites directly via the third

party. For example, to opt-out of Google’s analytic and marketing Sites, visit Google Analytics

Terms of Use, the Google Policy, or Google Analytics Opt-out.

14

Do Not Track. Please note that our Sites do not currently respond to browser-based “do not

track” signals. We will respond to any similar signals in the future as may be required by

applicable law.

Additional Marketing Rights and Choices

● Opt-out of Marketing: All individuals have the right to opt-out of receiving marketing

communications from MetaMetrics at any time. You may exercise your choices

regarding marketing communications by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link in emails we

send you, or you can please submit a request through Hub Support Contact Us or email

support@lexile.com.

● Direct Marketing: California residents and residents of certain other states may have the

right to request a list of Personal Information we have disclosed about you to third

parties for direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year.

● Withdrawing Your Consent/Opt-Out: You may withdraw any consent you have provided

at any time. The consequence of you withdrawing consent might be that we cannot

perform certain Sites for you, such as location-based Sites, personalizing or making

relevant certain types of advertising, or other Sites conditioned on your consent or

choice not to opt-out.

CHANGES AND QUESTIONS

How should you track changes to this Privacy Policy?

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will post a link to the updated policy in

the footer of all covered sites if changes are made, so we encourage you to visit any of our Sites

regularly to stay up to speed on changes to this Privacy Policy.

Additionally if using the Hub, Members will be informed via the Hub’s notification system. Your

continued use of the service constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy and any updates.

Where should you direct questions to us about thisPrivacy Policy?

If at any time you have questions or concerns about our privacy practices in general or this

Privacy Policy in particular, please feel free to contact us by sending an email to

support@lexile.com.

ADDITIONAL CCPA MANDATORY DISCLOSURES

For purposes of the CCPA, we add these supplemental disclosures, which are described in

further detail above in this Privacy Policy.

15

● Categories of Personal Information collected in the last 12 months: Identity Data,Contact Data, General Location Data, Device/Network Data, Commercial Data,Inference Data, Audio/Visual Data, User Content, Account Log-In Data, Financial Data.● Sources from which we collected Personal Information: information you voluntarilyprovided, automatic collection (cookies and similar technologies), third-partypartners/customers (schools, etc.), third party service providers.● Business Purposes of collecting Personal Information include: providing our Sites andservices, creating accounts, providing subscriptions, providing information yourequested, improving our Sites and services, inquiries and support, compliance, andanalytics.● Categories of Personal Information disclosed for a Business Purpose in the last 12months (business purposes for these disclosures are as described above):○ Disclosed to Service Providers, Partners, Affiliates, Google Analytics, orDisclosed With Consent: Identity Data, Contact Data, General Location Data,Device/Network Data, Account Log-In Data.○ Disclosed to Service Providers: Audio/Visual Data, Financial Data.● We have not “sold” or “shared” Personal Information (as defined by the CCPA) in the last12 months.

16
